Hey!
Sorry, sir. You can
talk to her all day long,
but you're not allowed to touch.
Wha...? No! It's not
what you think, Hitch! I just...
I heard that memories
could be transferred
between Titans like us
through physical contact.
So I... I wasn't trying to do anything
inappropriate to her just now, I promise.
I just thought I should give it a try
to see if I could discover anything.
Well, you are a boy at that age.
I bet you'd like to do
all kinds of 'discovering'
with Annie, if you could.
Okay, I'm really sorry!
Please don't ban me
from coming back, Hitch!
I wasn't planning to.
Annie would get bored out of her mind
if she only had me to talk to her.
Huh?
This is kind of annoying though.
How's she this popular
when all she does is sleep?
There isn't that much to talk about
when it comes to your crush,
but have you been
keeping up with the news
these past few days?
No.
Read this.
"The Military Continues to Cling to Power
Through the Wrongful
Detainment of Eren Jaeger."
People are really starting to
distrust the military.
I'm not sure what the brass
thought would happen
when they stopped giving
the public any answers.
In their defense,
it's not like we can go public
about Zeke and the Rumbling right now.
No one can save Eldia except Jaeger!
The new Eldian empire needs Eren Jaeger!
What is this?
Apparently there are protests like this
outside every local military base.
Hey,
Hitch! Lend us a hand, will ya?
Well crap. Guess I've
got work to do.
Armin!
Mikasa! There you are.
I'm glad to see you made it in.
Yeah. We need to
make use of this time
while we have it. Let's go.
Those are the new Scout recruits.
What are those kids doing here at HQ?
Okay, yes.
I did meet with Eren that day.
Oh?
I apologize for
hiding that fact until now.
It's proof enough that you were justified
in detaining the volunteers.
How very kind of you to own up to it.
This is through no fault of yours,
but you don't know
what the world is like.
It seemed to me that
you would keep waiting
to make a decision until it was too late.
And it was clear that Eren
had similar concerns.
I see.
So that's when you told Eren
to attack Marley alone,
so as to coerce the military
into taking action?
I wasn't quite that seditious.
Although, I did tell him that
the Military Government
was due for a wake-up call.
That's all you told him?
Why take the risk of
meeting Eren in secret
without attempting to lay out
some kind of concrete plan?
It was in secret, because as
a former soldier of Marley,
I realized that I was in
no position to request
even a public meeting.
So you understood that you were
gambling with our trust,
but the risk turned out
to be well worth it,
because it let you manipulate
Eren into following Zeke's plan.
What would be the point
in manipulating him?
I only wanted one thing!
For Eren Jaeger to know who I was!
No. That's not all.
We wanted Eren's Founding Titan
to crush Marley into dust.
And it worked.
Eren stood up for his principles
and brutalized Marley
just as we had hoped.
Actually. He went even further.
Eren answered our prayers for retribution
with a divine fury that we had
never dared to dream of.
And the fact that he was capable
of such an achievement
is proof that he carries
the Founding Titan.
Commander Pyxis.
Do you understand what's
unfolding right now,
before our very eyes?
We are witnessing a truly
decisive moment in history.
Very soon, two brothers
will reshape our whole world.
To be honest with you,
I just want to have
a decent view of the action.
It almost sounds like
the main reason you met Eren
was to slake your curiosity.
I suppose that's right.
For what it's worth,
I didn't tell any other
volunteers what I was up to.
I'm sure that you must see
my deception as a betrayal.
And it's true that
my actions were reckless.
But it's also true that I was
acting in Eldia's best interest.
I'd certainly like to believe you.
Towards that end, you'll need to recount
everything that you
and Eren talked about.
But first, a word of advice
about telling a lie.
To make it good,
you need to mix in at least
a pinch of the truth.
This is somewhere
between absurd and appalling.
How can people still doubt us
after all this time?
I thought we were comrades!
We spent three years sweating beside you
to build the railway and trade
systems that this island needed.
Your people are prospering because of us.
We gave Eldia everything we had, Hange.
I'm so sorry.
When we first opened
our railway ten months ago,
I didn't see this coming.
Yeah, you're telling me.
We swore to help fight for Eldia's future
and we meant every word...
Hange? What's the
matter with you?
Huh? Yelena went
behind the military's back
and met with Eren
in secret? Seriously?
Can you give me your word
that she didn't tell you?
She never so much as
dropped a hint. I promise.
Yeah. Your surprise seems
to be completely sincere.
To me, at any rate.
So she went that far.
You aren't saying that you can't believe
she would do it, and based off that,
I think you must know that
it's in character for her.
I don't exactly "know."
We may have approached it backwards,
but Yelena has given us a reason
to detain the volunteers.
Now. I need you to
tell me everything
you do know about her.
For the sake of our future.
My understanding is that it was Yelena
who first recruited the volunteers.
People were doubtful and wary,
so things didn't go so well at first.
More than once, Yelena proved
her loyalty to us and to Zeke
by getting her hands dirty.
Any Marleyan who doubted us
met with an untimely death.
Even when they were friends
who ate and slept beside us.
We overcame those losses
by telling ourselves
it was for the sake of the
homelands Marley stole from us.
That's funny.
Yelena's always argued
for Marleyan rights here.
She convinced us to let
Marleyan prisoners have jobs.
You make it sound like Yelena used to be
merciless to Marleyans.
Why would that change?
Right. Please come
with me, Onyankopon.
I need your help.
Huh?
I hear Hange's been
roaming all over the place.
Yes. The Commander's
been looking into
a few leads we dug up.
I know. I gave the
Commander permission
to take one of the
detained volunteers. But...
I'm afraid that I can't give
you two permission to meet Eren.
Why not, sir?
Because we've just confirmed that Eren
communicated with
the volunteers in secret.
This is likely what
incited him to attack Marley.
It's certainly something
he kept quiet about
leading up to the event.
We're currently in the
midst of an investigation
to see what all was said,
and who all was involved in this meeting.
Eren has maintained his silence
ever since these facts
were brought to light.
Furthermore, we're still
completely in the dark
about what he did during
his time alone in Marley.
I'm sorry to say that we believe that
Eren is being manipulated by Zeke.
I wouldn't have shared
these secrets with you
if you were anyone else,
so I'll ask that you
keep them to yourselves.
You really think that Eren would...
So what now? What will
you do with him?
Is that...?
Hm? Oh, it's nothing.
There was nowhere else to store the thing
so I had some recruits bring it up here.
Please hear me out, sir.
We've known Eren ever since we were kids.
If he refuses to talk to you,
that's all the more reason to send us in.
I know there's no guarantee that we can
get him to tell us the truth, but...
There isn't any harm in trying, right?
The situation is too delicate right now.
This conversation's over.
Why? You're right
that there'd be no harm in
letting us talk to him.
So why would he forbid it?
If I had to venture a guess,
it would be that the Military
has already decided he's a lost cause.
Excuse us!
If I'm right about that,
then they're probably
looking at candidates
to replace him with.
I'll listen through the door.
Hold on, Mikasa! You can't!
It's fine. They're not
gonna catch me.
You don't know that, and we
can't afford to take the risk.
We can't afford not to take that risk.
We need to find out what
the military's planning.
No matter what happens,
I won't let Eren be...
Armin! You okay?
I-I'm fine.
Oh, no!
Put out the fire! Quick!
Over here! We need a hand!
Hurry up and get over here!
Hey! Are you two all right?
Hitch! What was that?
The premier's office just exploded.
Has anyone seen him?
Give your hearts and souls!
Our anger's finally reached them!
The time has come for us to fight!
I'll fight right beside you!
Our hearts and souls, to the cause!
Premier Zachary had his "custom chair"
brought to his room today.
We believe that whoever
delivered the chair
must've planted a bomb in it.
In addition to the Premier himself,
the explosion killed three soldiers.
We don't know who was behind this
or what their motives were.
All but one of the volunteers
have been on house arrest,
and Onyankopon here was with me all day.
Then can you think of anyone else
who might've been responsible?
Before he died,
Premier Zachary said that
a group of recruits
brought the chair to his office.
Where were these recruits from?
He never told us what
branch they were with.
But as Mikasa and I were heading
to his room for our appointment,
we happened to notice a group of
recruits leaving HQ in a rush.
And those recruits were Scouts.
Speaking of your regiment.
I hear that a few of you Scouts
were arrested and charged
with leaking information
about Eren to the public.
Urgent news!
Eren Jaeger escaped!
He broke out of his underground cell!
Mobilize all troops and track him down!
Yes, sir!
Hurry. There's no time...
Armin. The hell is
going on right now?
Quite the crowd. This everyone?
In addition to our comrades here,
we have many who are
still within the military.
Such as the soldiers who killed
Dhalis Zachary with a bomb.
No one can save the Eldian Empire.
No one but you, Eren Jaeger.
It's okay, Mikasa.
Eren will understand.
If we can just talk to him,
then he'll understand.
Go find out where they're keeping Zeke.
His cohorts
have vanished from prison,
along with some one hundred
soldiers and guards.
It's apparent that they
planned for this mass desertion
to match the timing of Eren's escape.
And for the record, I have no doubt
that they perpetrated
the Premier's murder.
This group needs a name.
From this point on, let us refer to
these anti-military insurgents
as "the Jaegerists."
I can think of no one better
than Commander Hange
to tell us their goal.
In the short term,
their goal is to ensure that
Eren meets with his brother,
and in the long term,
they intend to reform the
military with Eren at its head.
They demonstrated their resolve
by way of assassinating our Premier.
It's obvious what provoked
them to act as they have.
They must've learned
about the Military's plan
to transfer the Founder.
Even though you kept it
secret from us Scouts.
Only because we knew
exactly what would happen
if we did tell you.
In any case.
Many of these Jaegerists
are from the Scouts.
How will you take responsibility
for their actions, Hange?
I'm willing to accept any punishment.
But I won't resign from my post.
That would be the height
of irresponsibility.
And there's a lot we don't know yet.
These Jaegerists could have
members hiding anywhere,
in any branch.
That's quite true.
In fact, I might be looking at some now.
Perhaps one of you will turn out
to be a suicide bomber.
Please. Don't be
ridiculous, Roeg.
We've been played for fools once.
So why should we trust you now?
Until the Scouts prove themselves,
they must be contained!
That's enough!
Remember that we have a guest here!
And even if that weren't the case,
this is no time to be
bickering amongst ourselves!
Hange. How many soldiers
know where Zeke is confined?
Captain Levi is guarding him
with an escort of 30 soldiers.
Then there're the three soldiers
who deliver supplies to them,
and aside from myself, that's it.
Please have those three brought here.
Nile. Is the Queen's
residence secure?
Its location is a well-kept secret,
but I'll look into it, anyway.
We know what Eren wants.
He'll seek out Zeke first.
And Historia if that fails.
So we must keep both of them
out of his reach at all costs.
Yes, sir!
Excuse me, sir.
You're our most senior commander.
So now that the Premier
has been assassinated,
the only person who can lead us is you.
What kind of strategy do you
think we should adopt right now?
Hmm. Well. It seems
to me they've got us beat,
so I was thinking we'd surrender.
Against enemies mixed within our ranks,
we have no other recourse.
Even if we did somehow manage
to smoke all of them out,
imagine how much blood
we would have to spill.
We don't have the time or the
numbers to waste on such folly.
It's the decisions we made as leaders
that caused these soldiers to desert us.
That's what brought about our defeat.
But, sir! You can't
actually intend to
bow down to the people who
murdered the Premier!
I knew Zachary for many years.
To live and die by revolution
is something that I think
he would've wanted.
And regardless, I don't think that
any of the four soldiers who were killed
would've wanted their deaths to be
the cause of Eldia's downfall.
So instead, you want us to
submit to the Jaeger brothers?
No, not entirely.
We'll use Zeke's location
to negotiate with Eren
and trust him to accept
that he has other enemies.
Once we've re-established peace,
we'll once again stake Eldia's survival
on a test-run of the Rumbling.
However, we will not bring up the subject
of how our leader was murdered.
We'll look past it.
If that is the price of saving hundreds,
or even thousands of our comrades...
then we'll pay it.
We've talked quite enough.
Now get to work!
Yes, Commander!
Commander Pyxis.
Please forgive that unseemly
display, Lady Azumabito.
It's fine. Every nation
goes through this.
Still, I'm afraid that I can't
guarantee your safety right now.
Until we're able to settle this matter,
I suggest that you wait at the port.
Right. We sincerely hope for
a swift end to this turmoil,
and for Eldia's victory.
Lady Mikasa. Please.
If things take a turn for the worse,
don't hesitate to make for our ship.
I'm grateful to you for offering,
and I appreciate your concern.
That being said,
I see myself as an Eldian.
I want to fight for
the future of the place
where I was born and raised.
So please don't worry about me.
What are you talking about?
You're the entire reason
we crossed the sea
to come to this place!
You came for our resources.
So long as we stay open to trade,
you don't care who leads this nation.
You just need the Rumbling
to succeed, right?
That's true.
If the promise of the Rumbling
turns out to be an empty one,
Hizuru will say our clan acted
alone and hang us out to dry.
Our investments will amount to nothing,
and the Azumabitos
will succumb to our debts.
Sounds like one more reason
that I shouldn't rely on you.
The Azumabito clan had no choice
but to adapt to these turbulent times.
But as a result, our prestige
has been reduced to the point
where we're now derided
as a pack of wretched,
money-grubbing vixens.
Still. We haven't lost
our pride as a clan,
any more than your mother had
when she engraved our
crest into your wrist.
No matter what becomes of this land,
we truly wish to protect you!
We're working with Eren
even though he killed the Premier?
Hey. Nobody knows
if he was behind that or not.
Keep your voice down, Mikasa.
People suspect us of
being Jaegerists as it is.
I'm still not sure whose side you're on.
Care to tell us?
Armin and I were there
when the bomb went off,
we almost got killed by the blast.
That answer your question?
Huh?
Enough.
Like Commander Pyxis said,
this is no time to
fight amongst ourselves.
What do you think of his plan?
Would you really be comfortable
entrusting all our fates
to Eren and Zeke?
No. This doesn't feel right.
Zeke and Yelena knew that they would
never be free of suspicion,
so they came up with an insurance plan.
And now, we're watching it pay out.
Our best bet is to assume that
they have more contingencies in place.
Let's focus on figuring out
what Zeke plans to do next,
before he makes even bigger
fools of us than he has.
If it turns out that I'm
getting worked up over nothing,
that'll be a welcome relief.
Do you have any leads in mind?
I noticed that Yelena secured
work for Marleyan prisoners
in a lot of strange places.
One good example would be restaurants.
This building's so big!
I've never seen anything like it!
Neither have I!
It must be your lucky day.
Y'all ready for some fancy dinin'?
Yeah!
Soldiers. Always
rushing off somewhere.
Gabi and Falco seek help
from a Marleyan prisoner of war.
Will the revelation of truth
result in a brightened future
or something else?
Next episode:
"Children of the Forest."